# Carleen Thio

Website: carleenthio.github.io E-mail: carleen.thio@gmail.com

Toronto, ON

#### Overview

An excellent and supportive team player that conducted user research and usability testing in two projects to develop a solution to real-world problems. Volunteered for the City of Toronto's committee advisor and animal service, requiring minimal supervision and developing good communication skills.

#### Education

## • University of Toronto

Toronto, ON 2019

Honours Bachelor of Science, Cognitive Science and Linguistic

- With a focus on Computational Cognition

### Design & Programming Skills

i dillillille Divillo		
Axure	InVision	Adobe XD
HTML	CSS	ReactJs
Javascript	Python	LaTeX
$\operatorname{Git}$	$\operatorname{Github}$	Xcode
Scrum	Agile	Prototyping

## Programming & Design Experience \_\_\_\_

• Content Writer

Remote work, Finland

Jan. 2020 - now

Typing Master

- Produce over 50 well-researched, family-friendly facts for the Type Rush game, which was utilized by them to improve children's' typing skills.
- Edited over 200 past facts for accuracy and truth, and reduced the number of characters to stay within the prescribed limit to ensure a smooth user experience for Type Rush.
- Designing 10 carefully written sentences, which contains all the alphabets at least once, for Typing Test to help analyse a user's typing skill.

# • UX Researcher & Designer [Axure RP] Project: FÜDGER for Design of Interactive Media

University of Toronto Jan. 2019 - Apr. 2019

- Developed and performed a detailed field study research on participant's grocery shopping habits to narrow down the food waste problem space.
- Conducted usability testing using a low-fidelity paper prototype to evaluate usability issues, which resulted in a redesign of features like the search button on the inventory page, which was not visible enough to users
- Reiterated high-fidelity prototype design after a few round of usability testing to understand user pain points, which created a friendlier user experience.

# • Researcher Project: Language Learning for Cognitive Science in Practice

University of Toronto Jan. 2019 - Apr. 2019

- Identified a linguistic problem involving a complex cognitive processes with a team in order to find a better solution for society, which resulted in helping language learners improve.
- Designed a more efficient language learning style for different levels of proficiency by conducting user research consisting of field research, interviews, and secondary research, creating an improved learning method.

# • Web Designer [HTML, CSS]

Global Engineering Week

Engineers Without Borders Dec. 2017 - Jan. 2018

- Redesigned their web page for the event to look more cohesive and appealing, which resulted in a simpler look and consistent colour scheme.
- Ensured functionality and information completeness before release by reading and testing the website, which resulted in findings such as the logo not returning users to the homepage.

# • Software Developer [Java]

University of Toronto

Project: Warehouse Simulator for Software Design

Winter 2017

- Collaborated with the team to develop a warehouse simulator and barcode scanner that provides tracking and updated status of the workers, inventory and facility to increase efficiency.
- Wrote extensive JUnit tests for the classes and majority of the code documentations to ensure all the codes are running correctly.

## • Software Developer[Java]

University of Toronto

Project: Photo Tagger for Software Design

Fall 2017

- Conceptualized an application that allows user to select and rename photos in their operating system, allowing it to be searched outside of the application by adding tags to the photos.
- Developed the structural design of the user interface using composite and facade design pattern to encapsulate the complex parts of the application.

## • Design & Technology Advisor

City of Toronto

Youth Design & Technology Committee

Feb. 2017 - Nov. 2017

Conducted qualitative research as the City of Toronto's Youth Design & Technology Advisory
Committee to identify gaps and provide improvements in the citys community centre, which
resulted in a short-term learning program.

#### Other Experiences

• Work Assistant

Toronto, ON

Sept. 2018 - Apr. 2019

Innis Café

- Created a seamless experience for customers by aiding daily activities such as taking orders, prepping food alongside the kitchen staff during rush hour, and ensuring coffee is always available, which reduces the number of customers waiting around the coffee section.
- Helped deliver food and prepare events, and ensured a smooth process throughout the event.
- Prepared invoices to be sent out to large order customers.

#### • Adoption Coordinator

Toronto Animal Service

Sep. 2016 - Feb. 2019

Toronto Animal Shelter

- Created a smooth adoption process by facilitating the screening process and understanding the adopter's situation to suggest suitable cats for them.
- Provided close attention and care for the cats' health, while being alert for signs of sickness, resulting in quick response from the Toronto Animal Service to provide appropriate care for the cat and reducing the spread of illness to the other cats.

## • Event Liaison

University of Toronto May 2018, May 2017

Science Rendezvous

 Promoted the linguistic department by overseeing several booths, which included explaining the nature of the language Inuktitut.

 Explained the concept and potential use of virtual reality to attendants by preparing the device and guiding them through it.